<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Elisha&#39;s Tomb</title>
    <link>https://a-mogs.netlify.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Elisha&#39;s Tomb</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://a-mogs.netlify.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Matthew 19:16-30</title>
        <link>https://a-mogs.netlify.com/post-2/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://a-mogs.netlify.com/post-2/</guid>
        <description>Elisha&#39;s Tomb https://a-mogs.netlify.com/post-2/ -&lt;h1 id=&#34;matthew-1916-30httpswwwbiblegatewaycompassagesearchmatthew193a16-30versionesv&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Matthew+19%3A16-30&amp;amp;version=ESV&#34;&gt;Matthew 19:16-30&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     There is a fatal snare in the initial question, “What good deed must I do to have eternal life?” (verse 16) The response elucidates the question’s error: “Why do you ask me about what is good? There is only one who is good.” (verse 17) We cannot make the mistake of assuming that our salvation is dependent upon our deeds. Here, Christ is hinting that salvation, goodness, is dependent upon the Lord, whom if the man had a relationship with, he would not have needed to ask the question. Further, the “good deeds” that fill the life of someone who is saved would be found in obedience. God has given us laws to obey and if we love him, we ought to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     If we investigate the commandments, the “good deeds,” cited by Christ in verses 18 and 19, we notice that they do not ask for the completion of a task, but a lifetime of obedience. Commandments that start with “You shall not…” inherently require a lifetime for “satisfaction” of the law. These are not commands to abstain from murder, adultery, stealing, or false witness, for a brief period of time, but forever! At no point in someone’s life will he be able to check off a box that says he completed this commandment, until the day of his death! The same goes for honoring our parents and, especially, for loving our neighbor. Buying Mother’s Day gifts or doing our chores is not sufficiently honoring our parents. Giving money to the poor or picking up someone’s dropped groceries is not sufficiently loving our neighbors. These are mere instances that &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be telling of an obedient lifestyle. The intrinsic commitment in these commandments speaks to the longevity of goodness’ requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     But this is not what the young man was looking for. He was not interested in a way of life; he wanted a to-do list, not a creed. Why? Because if he was given an assignment that he can turn into the Teacher that would grant him a passing grade for salvation, he could live the rest of his life however he likes. He wanted a license that would not only grant him freedom from responsibility, but freedom from the burden of guilt. This is revealed in the question “All these I have kept. What do I still lack?” (verse 20) If he was so (foolishly) confident in his obedience, he should have walked away feeling content about himself. If it was true that he was perfect in his obedience to these commandments, he should have been able to continue to live in such obedience and arrive at salvation (at least, according to the flow of this conversation). But he understood that he was lacking, so he sought an alternative, an escape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     The young man wanted a task&amp;ndash;a quest that could be completed, a holy grail that could be found, an enemy that could be slain. Jesus obliged. But he did so, as always, by delivering the exact answer the young man needed to hear: “If you would be perfect, go, sell what you possess and give to the poor, and you will have treasure in heaven; and come, follow me.” (verse 21) Jesus speaks to what is inside this man’s heart. If he really wanted to be perfect, as he inwardly knows he is not, and if he wanted to address the source of his spiritual dissatisfaction, then he must surrender everything. And this answer drove the young man to despair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     Why did the young man become despondent? Because he came face-to-face with his spiritually crippling desire to live how he wanted. See, the young man did not want a relationship with God; he wanted freedom from God! He wanted to satisfy God so he could be his own god. Jesus asked him to sell his possessions, but the young man realized that he could not. Why is it so difficult for a rich man to enter heaven? Because the more possessions you have, the more difficult it is to let them go. However, these “possessions” are not limited to material wealth; this can be applied to time, to talents, to any sort of blessing. In the middle of a packed schedule, we can give thirty minutes to the Lord. But when we have an abundance of free time, how much of that time do we spend in personal devotions and how much of it do we spend in leisure? Why are less talented laymen more willing to humbly serve on worship teams while the abundantly talented use their gifts to seek fame and self glory? We should not find comfort in verses 23-24 because we may be materially poor; we are equally hopeless as this young man in surrendering everything to the Lord. We have the same desire to hold onto our possessions in hopes of becoming our own gods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     We should instead arrive at the same despair as the disciples when they asked, “Who then can be saved?” (verse 25) We cannot fool ourselves, like this young man, that we are perfect in obedience. We should realize that we would never be able to fully obey these commandments even for a brief period of time, not to mention the required lifetime. But the alternative gives no more hope because we are equally unable to surrender what is ours. Jesus’ answer first sinks us into the greatest depths of despair, then lifts us to the single, greatest hope. “With man this is impossible, but with God all things are possible.” (verse 27) I don’t know exactly what went through the disciples’ minds when they heard this, but here we can find the only source of hope. Jesus affirms our worries that we cannot be perfectly obedient, and he assures us that we will never be perfectly obedient. But if “with God all things are possible,” what else can we do but turn to him? As present-day people, we know our source of hope: the cross. Because we are unable to be obedient, Christ had to be. Because we had to die for our sins, Christ chose to in our stead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     Then do we find that license to live however we’d like in the cross? Do we arrive at the destination that the young man sought? No. Because in a moment of ingenuity, Peter understood that the Christian life is by definition a life of surrender. “See, we have left everything and followed you.” (verse 27) “Everything” he says! Christ may not call all of us to ever surrender all of our material possessions, but if he so chooses, we should not struggle. Why? Because everything that we own has long since been given to God; all of our possessions are no longer ours. If so, how preposterous is it to spend my time doing whatever I want; my time belongs to the Lord! If so, how ridiculous is it to spend my money on whatever I want; my wealth belongs to the Lord! If so, how absurd is it to spend my talents for my own sake; my talents belong to the Lord! In fact, how dare I continue to prodigally spend these things as if they still were mine! So the first application for myself, as a redeemed Christian, is to understand that my life, and everything in it, belongs to the Lord. That is what it means to be a Christian. That means every second of my time, every ounce of talent, and every cent I possess is used for God’s glory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     Then what does this mean for rest and recreation? It is true that we are commanded to rest. But in the command of resting on the seventh day, we are commanded to be working for six days. As for recreation, I can say, with confidence from anecdotal experience, that there is nothing more gratifying, satisfying, and enjoyable than living for the Lord. The pleasure derived from pursuing the desires of our flesh pale in comparison to the fulfillment provided in glorifying the Lord. I say these things not as mere pious drivel. Because when I lay my head at the end of a productive day of work and personal devotion, I can sleep with a sense of accomplishment. After a day of idleness, I ruefully disdain sleep because I know I wasted the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;    The second application is that I should be wary of complacency. This surrender that we are called to is just as out of reach as a life of perfect obedience; it is something that we strive towards rather than fully achieve. If the thought “I’ve done enough” ever crosses my mind, I have fallen into a pit of spiritual death. Then am I no better off than I was before the cross? No, because while frustration will inevitably be a part of my pursuit of surrender, despair should never be. Instead, I live in gratitude of Jesus taking upon the impossible burden in my stead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;    Finally, I am confident in the value of the prize I am seeking. Jesus assures us that everything we give up will be gained a hundredfold. In Matthew 16:26, Christ says, “For what will it profit a man if he gains the whole world and forfeits his soul?” This assures us that the prize we are working towards is worth far more than anything the world can offer.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://a-mogs.netlify.com/post-2/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Chapter I: The Grand Hall</title>
        <link>https://a-mogs.netlify.com/post-1/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://a-mogs.netlify.com/post-1/</guid>
        <description>Elisha&#39;s Tomb https://a-mogs.netlify.com/post-1/ -&lt;p&gt;Three hundred and forty-eight years, six months, and nineteen days ago
to-day, the Parisians awoke to the sound of all the bells in the triple
circuit of the city, the university, and the town ringing a full peal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sixth of January, 1482, is not, however, a day of which history has
preserved the memory. There was nothing notable in the event which thus
set the bells and the bourgeois of Paris in a ferment from early morning.
It was neither an assault by the Picards nor the Burgundians, nor a hunt
led along in procession, nor a revolt of scholars in the town of Laas, nor
an entry of “our much dread lord, monsieur the king,” nor even a pretty
hanging of male and female thieves by the courts of Paris. Neither was it
the arrival, so frequent in the fifteenth century, of some plumed and
bedizened embassy. It was barely two days since the last cavalcade of that
nature, that of the Flemish ambassadors charged with concluding the
marriage between the dauphin and Marguerite of Flanders, had made its
entry into Paris, to the great annoyance of M. le Cardinal de Bourbon,
who, for the sake of pleasing the king, had been obliged to assume an
amiable mien towards this whole rustic rabble of Flemish burgomasters, and
to regale them at his Hôtel de Bourbon, with a very “pretty morality,
allegorical satire, and farce,” while a driving rain drenched the
magnificent tapestries at his door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What put the “whole population of Paris in commotion,” as Jehan de Troyes
expresses it, on the sixth of January, was the double solemnity, united
from time immemorial, of the Epiphany and the Feast of Fools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On that day, there was to be a bonfire on the Place de Grève, a maypole at
the Chapelle de Braque, and a mystery at the Palais de Justice. It had
been cried, to the sound of the trumpet, the preceding evening at all the
cross roads, by the provost’s men, clad in handsome, short, sleeveless
coats of violet camelot, with large white crosses upon their breasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the crowd of citizens, male and female, having closed their houses and
shops, thronged from every direction, at early morn, towards some one of
the three spots designated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each had made his choice; one, the bonfire; another, the maypole; another,
the mystery play. It must be stated, in honor of the good sense of the
loungers of Paris, that the greater part of this crowd directed their
steps towards the bonfire, which was quite in season, or towards the
mystery play, which was to be presented in the grand hall of the Palais de
Justice (the courts of law), which was well roofed and walled; and that
the curious left the poor, scantily flowered maypole to shiver all alone
beneath the sky of January, in the cemetery of the Chapel of Braque.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The populace thronged the avenues of the law courts in particular, because
they knew that the Flemish ambassadors, who had arrived two days
previously, intended to be present at the representation of the mystery,
and at the election of the Pope of the Fools, which was also to take place
in the grand hall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was no easy matter on that day, to force one’s way into that grand
hall, although it was then reputed to be the largest covered enclosure in
the world (it is true that Sauval had not yet measured the grand hall of
the Château of Montargis). The palace place, encumbered with people,
offered to the curious gazers at the windows the aspect of a sea; into
which five or six streets, like so many mouths of rivers, discharged every
moment fresh floods of heads. The waves of this crowd, augmented
incessantly, dashed against the angles of the houses which projected here
and there, like so many promontories, into the irregular basin of the
place. In the centre of the lofty Gothic* façade of the palace, the grand
staircase, incessantly ascended and descended by a double current, which,
after parting on the intermediate landing-place, flowed in broad waves
along its lateral slopes,—the grand staircase, I say, trickled
incessantly into the place, like a cascade into a lake. The cries, the
laughter, the trampling of those thousands of feet, produced a great noise
and a great clamor. From time to time, this noise and clamor redoubled;
the current which drove the crowd towards the grand staircase flowed
backwards, became troubled, formed whirlpools. This was produced by the
buffet of an archer, or the horse of one of the provost’s sergeants, which
kicked to restore order; an admirable tradition which the provostship has
bequeathed to the constablery, the constablery to the _maréchaussée_,
the _maréchaussée_ to our _gendarmeri_ of Paris.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://a-mogs.netlify.com/post-1/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss> 